<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>vortices | joovonkim</title>
    <link>/tag/vortices/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/vortices/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>vortices</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Joo-Von Kim (2020)</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 10:48:48 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hu0b7a4cb9992c9ac0e91bd28ffd38dd00_9727_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>vortices</title>
      <link>/tag/vortices/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHIPMuNCS</title>
      <link>/project/chipmuncs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 10:48:48 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/chipmuncs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chaos-based-information-processing-with-magnetic-nano-oscillators&#34;&gt;Chaos-based information processing with magnetic nano-oscillators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Project website: 
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chipmuncs.universite-paris-saclay.fr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.chipmuncs.universite-paris-saclay.fr&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I am the coordinator of CHIPMuNCS, which is a frontier research project at the interface between nanomagnetism, spintronics, and nonlinear dynamics. It is motivated by the premise that the rich behaviour of nonlinear systems, in particular chaos, can be leveraged for alternative paradigms for computing and information processing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary objective is to establish the utility and feasibility of the nanocontact vortex oscillator, a nanoscale spintronic device, as a universal building block for chaos-based information processing by demonstrating three technological functionalities: random number generation, secure communications, and nonlinear computing. The underlying idea is that the complexity required for computation and possible cognitive functions can be generated within a single system, without the need of a complex array of interconnected subsystems. The project addresses the pressing challenges raised by the current information revolution, with the exponential growth of digital data, spurred by the internet, the ubiquity of “smartphones”, and unprecedented scientific advances in data-intensive fields from genetics to social networks. Identifying useful patterns amongst such vast oceans of bits is a timely and formidable challenge for current technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project consortium members are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.c2n.universite-paris-saclay.fr/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Centre de Nanosciences et de Nanotechnologies&lt;/a&gt; (CNRS/Univ. Paris-Saclay), Palaiseau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;http://lmops.univ-lorraine.fr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Laboratoire Matériaux Optiques, Photonique et Systèmes&lt;/a&gt; (CentraleSupélec/Univ. Lorraine), Metz&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://ijl.univ-lorraine.fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Institut Jean Lamour&lt;/a&gt; (CNRS/Univ. Lorraine), Nancy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://cnrs-thales.fr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Unité Mixte de Physique&lt;/a&gt; (CNRS/Thales/Univ. Paris-Saclay), Palaiseau&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;CHIPMuNCS is funded by the 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://anr.fr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Agence Nationale de la Recherche&lt;/a&gt; under grant number ANR-17-CE24-0008.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project runs from 1 February 2018 to 31 January 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Analytical model of the inertial dynamics of a magnetic vortex</title>
      <link>/publication/yoo-2020-arxiv-vortex/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Jun 2020 14:04:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/yoo-2020-arxiv-vortex/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pattern generation and symbolic dynamics in a nanocontact vortex oscillator</title>
      <link>/publication/yoo-2020-il/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/publication/yoo-2020-il/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChaoSpin</title>
      <link>/project/chaospin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2018 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/chaospin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;chaos-based-information-processing-using-spintronic-nano-oscillators&#34;&gt;Chaos-based information processing using spintronic nano-oscillators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;ChaoSpin was a frontier research project at the interface between nanomagnetism, spintronics, and nonlinear dynamics. The project was led by Dr. Myoung-Woo Yoo as part of his Marie Skłodowska-Curie fellowship that ran from 1 February 2018 to 31 January 2020.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project was motivated by the premise that the rich behaviour of nonlinear systems, in particular chaos, can be leveraged for alternative computing paradigms. The primary objective was to establish the utility and feasibility of the nanocontact vortex oscillator, a nanoscale spintronic device, as a universal building block for chaos-based information processing by demonstrating key technological functionalities, such as random number generation and communication using symbolic dynamics. The underlying idea is that the complexity required for computation and possible cognitive functions can be generated within a single system, without the need of a complex array of interconnected subsystems. The project built upon the NOMADE group’s discovery of novel commensurate and chaotic phases in the nanocontact vortex oscillator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project objectives were defined by three scientific questions related to magnetic vortex dynamics on the nanoscale, namely:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can the chaotic state be detected experimentally?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does the chaotic state respond to external forcing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can the chaotic state be exploited for information processing?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These questions were addressed by combining the use of high-performance simulation tools and quantitative theories with state-of-the-art experiments involving high-frequency electrical characterisation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project has funded by the Horizon2020 Research Framework Programme of the European Commission under contract no. 751344.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
